<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matheus Mortatti&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://matheusmortatti.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matheus Mortatti&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 19:15:42 -0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://matheusmortatti.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolfbit Postmortem</title>
      <link>http://matheusmortatti.com/posts/wolfbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 19:15:42 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://matheusmortatti.com/posts/wolfbit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wolfbit was a game done by me and two other friends for the Ludum Dare 35 and the LowRez Jam 2016, where I was responsible for the art, oddly enough. It was a different experience for me, as I never had done any pixel art before in my life and I had to do it in three days in a sort of decent way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div allign=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://matheusmortatti.com/images/wolfbit.gif&#34; alt=&#34;wolfbit&#34; /&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme of the jam was &amp;ldquo;Shapeshift&amp;rdquo;. Before starting, me and my friends agreed to create a simple game that didn&amp;rsquo;t made us stay up late and loose our minds with the time pressure. So, to do that, we decided to participate in the LowRez Jam too, that made us limit our resolution to 64px. That was a great way to limit the art (and make it a little bit easier) and limit what we could accomplish in such a small resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we decided to play with the character shapeshifting as well as the controls on the keyboard. We came up with the context of an werewolf running away from angry villagers, and made the WASD keys change up to any key on the keyboard. That created an urgency effect that fitted pretty well the context of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the three days of the jam, we took it pretty easy. We got a lot of sleep and worked just enough to get the job done, so much so that the game was only playable in the final hours of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jam ended and it was time for people to play the game. We got quite a lot of feedback from our friends and the ludum dare site. We took the time to play a lot of other people&amp;rsquo;s games and comment on them and that led to people coming to play our game. That&amp;rsquo;s something pretty awesome about Ludum Dare that I never get on any other jam! Since it was my first one, I was kind of amazed with the feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div allign=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://matheusmortatti.com/images/wolfbitAnalytics.png&#34; alt=&#34;wolfbit&#34; /&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, people enjoyed the game more than we expected. Our friends gathered around to beat each other&amp;rsquo;s highscore before classes and it was great! We then decided then to put in an online scoreboard for people to compete with each other and that made the game even more awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even tho the art was kind of half baked and I didn&amp;rsquo;t really knew what I was doing, I was happy with the game. People enjoyed the black and whit art style and the music was very fitting, with a touch of castlevania nostalgy if I may say so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://matheusmortatti.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 14:02:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://matheusmortatti.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an Undergrad student in Computer Engineering at University of Campinas (UNICAMP - Brazil) who is trying his luck with game development!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I&amp;rsquo;m programming random games for learning purposes and studying Computer Graphics by my own. The OpenGL waters are DEEP AND I&amp;rsquo;M DROWNING HELP. I&amp;rsquo;m also starting to research Deep Learning topics and have worked on a few projects about it during the CE course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides that, I try to create some pixel art from time to time and think about stories, plots and mechanics to fit the games I dream of making. Game Design is very very interesting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check out my &lt;a href=&#34;../pdf/matheus-mortatti-cv.pdf&#34;&gt;CV&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://matheusmortatti.itch.io&#34;&gt;games i&amp;rsquo;ve worked on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>